<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Back-End Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://christianmendoza.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://christianmendoza.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-27T21:37:44-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://christianmendoza.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Christian Mendoza]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gitting to Know Ruby]]></title>
    <link href="http://christianmendoza.github.io/blog/2013/10/26/gitting-to-know-ruby/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-26T16:09:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://christianmendoza.github.io/blog/2013/10/26/gitting-to-know-ruby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We went over a lot of things during the last class. It started off with a command line/terminal and Git/Github refresher, and then we jumped right into the meaty stuff: Ruby!</p>

<p>We started writing simple Ruby code into IRB (Interactive Ruby Shell), learning about objects and calling some methods and operators. Objects in Ruby respond to messages sent. We learned a little about “Syntactic Sugar,” which is syntax that is designed to make things easier to read or to express. One example is:</p>

<p><code>"steven".send : upcase</code>
<code>"steven".upcase</code> <em>#syntactic sugar</em></p>

<p>I completed our homework assignment, including the extra one. It was great practice to program Classes and get the code to pass the tests. I’m looking forward to learning more material next class!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Git!]]></title>
    <link href="http://christianmendoza.github.io/blog/2013/10/21/learning-git/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-21T21:10:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://christianmendoza.github.io/blog/2013/10/21/learning-git</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my first blog post, using Octopress, Mou and Git. Here are a few things Steve taught us today:</p>

<p><code>$ git init</code> <em>#Hey Git, start watching everything in this folder</em></p>

<p><code>$ git add .</code> <em>#Hey Git, add everything in this folder to the staging area</em></p>

<p><code>$ git status</code> <em>#Hey Git, what’s going on?</em></p>

<p><code>$ git diff</code> <em>#Hey Git, show me the differences between now and the last commit</em></p>

<p><code>$ git commit -m "Message"</code> <em>#Hey Git, you can take a snapshot now of everything I staged</em></p>

<p><code>$ git checkout "filename"</code> <em>#Hey Git, I was dumb and accidentally deleted this file. Please bring it back from the dead</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
